

VÍCTOR PÉREZ PIQUERAS

Software Engineer - Scrum Master - Researcher



+34 601 13 94 14



victorperezpiqueras@gmail.com @victorperezpiqueras in victor-pérez-piqueras





ABOUT ME

I'm a professional, competent and passionate Software Engineer. I'm experienced in web development, frontend design and UI. I also have knowledge in backend, ReST APIs and database design, which allows me to easily adapt to most job positions, being able to work as a full-stack developer.

I enjoy teamworking and pursuing sinergies to get the best of me and the team. I've developed most of my career in english and, thus, I can effectively communicate with my coworkers whether they speak english or spanish.

I'm devoted to clean code practices, design patterns, refactoring principles and continuous integration/deployment techniques. Solid Agile defender and PSM-II.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer & Scrum Master

Nov. 2021 - Today

Grupo Vermon S.L.

Development of a system for track and fleet monitoring in the rail transport sector. Project in an international, Scrum-managed team (recently holding Scrum Master role), using current technologies such as Angular for frontend and AWS Cloud services for the infrastructure and backend architecture.



Researcher

Feb. 2021 - Oct. 2021

Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha

Research support staff in R&D&i project. Design and evaluation of multi-objective optimization algorithms. Technologies: Python, Pandas.



Full Stack Developer - Internship

Jul. 2020 - Sep. 2020

Development of a web application for the creation and management of dynamic forms to control incidents in companies. Technologies: Angular, AWS Serverless.



Grupo Vermon S.L.

Jun. 2019 - Aug. 2019

Full stack development of a web application for real-time home sensor management and monitoring. Technologies: Angular, Python Flask, SQLite.

EDUCATION



Certified Cloud Practitioner • AWS

2023



Professional Scrum Master II • Scrum.org

2023 2021 - Today



PhD In Advanced Computer Technologies Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha



Part-time researcher at the Intelligent Systems and Data Mining Laboratory.



Masters Degree In Computer Science

2020 - 2021

2016 - 2020



Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha

Multidisciplinary training and management skills. 5 distinctions with honours.

- TFM: "Scrum management software enhancement for automatic Product Backlog prioritization". Technologies: Angular, NodeJS, MySQL, AWS Serverless. Mark: 10.



Agile development & Scrum

HARD SKILLS

Web development A





Clean Code, CI/CD, Testing (



Bachelor's Bilingual Degree In Computer Science

Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha Mention in Software Engineering. 4 distinctions with honours.

- TFG: "TheProductOwnerd: Support tool for the Product Owner". Technologies: Angular, NodeJS, MySQL. Mark: 10.

First Certificate In English (B2) • Cambridge

2018

ADDITIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS



SISTEDES - NTT Data Award for the best Masters Thesis

2022

National award for the best Masters Thesis on new methodologies and tools for software development.



Charles Babbage Award for the best Masters Thesis

2021

Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha

Award for the best Master's Thesis of a multidisciplinary nature and business transfer in the Masters Degree In Computer Science.



Universidad De Castilla-la Mancha Average mark of 9,80.

Pictotrainer - Third Award • Esiiab • Hack For Albacity

2020

2021

Web and mobile application for the training and rehabilitation of people with functional diversity, presented to the HackForAlbacity2020 competition in collaboration with the CRMF-IMSERSO.



Self learning

Teamwork

Critical thinking

Creativity



